Guide to the Charles Frederick Chandler Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Subject Files, Dates
  - Glucose
    - Correspondence, 1872-1890, (3 Folders) (Box 183, Folder 1 to 3)
    - National Academy of Sciences Report
      - Clippings and Notes (Box 183, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1881-1884, (2 Folders) (Box 183, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Drafts, (5 Folders) (Box 184, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Report, 1883 (Box 184, Folder 6)
      - Report, 1884 (Box 184, Folder 7)
    - Patents (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - Glycerine (Box 185, Folder 2)
  - Gold and Silver
    - Articles, (4 Folders) (Box 185, Folder 3 to 6)
    - Articles (Box 186)
    - Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 187, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 187, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 188, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1867-1892 (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - Halogens (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Hydrogen (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Hydrometer
    - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 188, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Articles (Box 189, Folder 1)
    - Chandler article on Baume Hydrometer, 1881 (Box 189, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and Notes, (5 Folders) (Box 189, Folder 3 to 7)
    - Correspondence, 1881-1896 (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Ice
    - Advertisements (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Articles (Box 190, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 190, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1872-1889 (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 190, Folder 5 to 6)
    - J. Eastman Refrigeration Case, 1881-1888 (Box 190, Folder 7)
    - Patents (Box 190, Folder 8)
    - Patents (Box 191, Folder 1)
  - Industrial Chemistry
    - General (Box 191, Folder 2)
    - Patents (Box 191, Folder 3)
  - Ink
    - Correspondence, 1873-1905 (Box 191, Folder 4)
    - Declaration of Independence Restoration, 1875-1880 (Box 191, Folder 5)
    - Forged Check Case Notes (Box 191, Folder 6)
  - Ionone (Box 191, Folder 7)
  - Iron and Steel
    - Analyses (Box 191, Folder 9)
    - Articles (Box 191, Folder 10)
    - Articles, (5 Folders) (Box 192, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Chandler's Report for Bath iron Mining and Manufacturing Co., 1866 (Box 192, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 193, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Correspondence, 1868-1924, (2 Folders) (Box 193, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Legal Case Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 193, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Legal Case Notes (Box 194, Folder 1)
    - Legal Documents, (4 Folders) (Box 194, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Jute (Box 194, Folder 4)
  - Ketone (Box 194, Folder 5)
  - Lead and Lead Paint
    - Advertisements (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 194, Folder 7)
    - Clippings and Notes, (5 Folders) (Box 195, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Correspondence, 1860-1888, (2 Folders) (Box 195, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Light and Optics
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 196)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 197, Folder 1)
    - Optical Instruments, 1883-1893, (4 Folders) (Box 197, Folder 2 to 5)
    - Microscopy Articles and Pamphlets (Box 197, Folder 6)
    - Microscopy Articles and Pamphlets, (2 Folders) (Box 198, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Magnetism (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - Manganese, (2 Folders) (Box 198, Folder 4 to 6)
  - Manganese (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - Medicine and Pharmacology
    - Advertisements and Price Lists (Box 199, Folder 2)
    - Articles, (2 Folders) (Box 199, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Chandler Lecture "What Chemistry had Done for Pharmacy," 1911 (Box 199, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1875-1907 (Box 199, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 199, Folder 7)
    - Legal Cases
      - Aristol (Box 200, Folder 1)
      - Veronal Case, 1909, (2 Folders) (Box 200, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Mercury, (2 Folders) (Box 200, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Meteorites
    - Articles and Publications, (4 Folders) (Box 201, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Articles and Publications (Box 202, Folder 1)
    - Chandler's Meteorite Collection- Notes and Description (Box 202, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 202, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Correspondence, 1881-1892 (Box 202, Folder 6)
    - Lecture Notes (Box 202, Folder 7)
  - Microbiology
    - Advertisements (Box 202, Folder 8)
    - Articles and Publications, (4 Folders) (Box 203, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Chandler Lecture on Germ Theory of Disease, 1874 (Box 203, Folder 5)
    - Chandler Article on Fermentation (Box 203, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 203, Folder 7)
    - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 204, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Correspondence, 1860-1889 (Box 204, Folder 5)
  - Mortar (Box 204, Folder 6)
  - Milk
    - Adulteration
      - Chandler's Article for Johnson's Encyclopedia (Box 205, Folder 1)
      - Clippings and Notes (Box 205, Folder 2)
    - Advertisements (Box 205, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 205, Folder 4 to 6)
    - Articles and Publications (Box 206)
    - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 207, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Bibliography and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 207, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Chemical Analyses
      - Articles and Publications (Box 207, Folder 5)
      - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 208, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 208, Folder 3 to 5)
      - Clippings and Notes (Box 209-210)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 211, Folder 1)
    - Condensed Milk, 1868-1899, (2 Folders) (Box 211, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Correspondence, 1869-1897 (Box 211, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Lactometer, (2 Folders) (Box 212, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Legal Cases
      - Clippings (Box 212, Folder 3)
      - Daniel Schrumpf Case, 1876, (3 Folders) (Box 212, Folder 4 to 6)
      - Miscellaneous Legal Documents, 1876-1883 (Box 213, Folder 1)
    - Legislation (Box 213, Folder 2)
    - Pictures and Plates (Box 213, Folder 3)
    - Pricing and Trade (Box 213, Folder 4)
    - Printing Blocks (Images used for The American Chemist) (Box 213, Folder 5)
    - "Report on Milk" Manuscript, 1883 (Box 213, Folder 6)
  - Mineral Waters
    - Advertisements (Box 214-215)
    - Articles and Publications (Box 216)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 217)
    - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 218, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Correspondence, 1863-1911, (2 Folders) (Box 218, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Correspondence, 1863-1911 (Box 219)
    - Lecture Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 220, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Legal Cases
      - New York Carbonic Acid Gas Case, 1910, (2 Folders) (Box 220, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Saratoga Springs Case, 1909, (4 Folders) (Box 221, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Saratoga Star Spring (Box 221, Folder 5)
  - Mineralogy
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 222, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Clippings and Notes (Clippings and Notes) (Box 222, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Correspondence, 1872-1880 (Box 223, Folder 1)
    - Crystallography, (2 Folders) (Box 223, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Lecture Notes (Box 223, Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 223, Folder 5)
  - Nabisco
    - Advertisements and Promotional Material (Box 224, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1902-1919 (Box 224, Folder 2)
    - Earl Babst (Box 224, Folder 3)
    - Legal Cases
      - Confectionary Cases, 1905, (2 Folders) (Box 224, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Uniform Weight Legislation (Box 224, Folder 6)
      - Legal Documents, (5 Folders) (Box 225, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 225, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Naval Observatory
    - Correspondence (Box 226, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 226, Folder 2)
    - Government Documents and Reports, 1899-1902, (3 Folders) (Box 226, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Memoranda (Box 226, Folder 6)
    - Board of Visitors Appointment (signed by T. Roosevelt) (Box 227)
  - Nickel
    - Articles and Publications (Box 228, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 228, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Correspondence, 1866-1910 (Box 228, Folder 4)
  - Nitrogen and Nitrogen Compounds
    - General (Box 229, Folder 1)
    - Ammonia, (3 Folders) (Box 229, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 229, Folder 5 to 8)
    - Cyanides, (3 Folders) (Box 229, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Nitrogen Products Co. Correspondence, 1912-1916 (Box 229, Folder 12)
  - Oil
    - General, 1871-1902 (Box 229, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1900-1916 (Box 229, Folder 14)
    - Hydrogenated Oils
      - Bibliography (Box 229, Folder 15)
      - Clippings and Notes (Box 229, Folder 16)
    - Legal Cases
      - Artificial Camphor Oil Case, 1906 (Box 229, Folder 17)
      - Artificial Camphor Oil Case, 1906, (2 Folders) (Box 230, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Pine Oil Case, 1911 (Box 230, Folder 3)
      - Rosin Oils (Box 230, Folder 4)
      - Shellac Cases, 1872-1884, (2 Folders) (Box 230, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Southern Oil Company Cotton Seed Oil Case, 1914, (3 Folders) (Box 230, Folder 7 to 9)
  - Omnalit, 1904 (Box 230, Folder 10)
  - Organic Chemistry
    - Lecture Notes (Box 230, Folder 11)
  - Oxygen
    - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 230, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 230, Folder 14)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 231, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1889-1920 (Box 231, Folder 2)
    - Patents (Box 231, Folder 3)
  - Ozone (Box 231, Folder 4)
  - Paint
    - Advertisements (Box 231, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1870-1880, (2 Folders) (Box 231, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Legal Documents, (6 Folders) (Box 231, Folder 8 to 13)
    - Notes and Analyses (Box 231, Folder 14)
  - Paper
    - Advertisements, (2 Folders) (Box 231, Folder 15 to 16)
    - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 231, Folder 17 to 18)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 231, Folder 19)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 232, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Correspondence, 1870-1921 (Box 232, Folder 4)
    - Legal Documents
      - General, (2 Folders) (Box 232, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Collar Case, 1871-1872 (Box 232, Folder 7)
      - Paper Case, 1899 (Box 232, Folder 8)
      - Waterproofing Patents (Box 232, Folder 9)
    - National Academy of Sciences Committee on Waterproofing Paper, 1875-1876 (Box 232, Folder 10)
  - Perfume
    - Artificial Musk, 1898-1903, (4 Folders) (Box 232, Folder 11 to 14)
    - Ionone (Rose Scent), (2 Folders) (Box 232, Folder 15 to 16)
  - Petroleum
    - Articles and Publications, (4 Folders) (Box 233, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Chandler Article- Notes and Drafts (Box 233, Folder 5)
    - Asphalt, 1912 (Box 233, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 233, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Correspondence, 1872-1915 (Box 233, Folder 9)
    - Pavement Case, 1914 (Box 233, Folder 10)
  - Phenacetin
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 233, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1899-1906 (Box 233, Folder 12)
    - Legal Documents, (3 Folders) (Box 233, Folder 13 to 15)
    - Legal Documents, (4 Folders) (Box 234, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Notes (Box 234, Folder 5)
  - Phosphorus
    - Articles and Publications (Box 234, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 234, Folder 7 to 9)
    - Correspondence, 1871-1878 (Box 234, Folder 10)
  - Photography
    - Advertisements (Box 234, Folder 11)
    - ANSCO Case, 1901-1914 (Box 234, Folder 12)
    - Camera-C.P. Stirn Concealed Vest Camera (Box 277)
    - Celluloid Film
      - Correspondence, 1876-1914 (Box 234, Folder 13)
      - Notes (Box 234, Folder 14)
      - Notes (Box 235, Folder 1)
      - Notes and Experiments, (2 Folders) (Box 235, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Legal Cases
        - Case Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 235, Folder 4 to 5)
        - Case Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 236, Folder 1 to 3)
        - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 236, Folder 4 to 5)
        - Legal Documents (Box 237)
      - Patents, (4 Folders) (Box 238, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Chandler Article on Photography- Drafts and Notes (Box 238, Folder 5)
    - Clippings (Box 238, Folder 6)
    - Clippings (Box 239)
    - Clippings, (2 Folders) (Box 240, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Albertypes (Box 240, Folder 3)
      - Applications Collotypes (Box 240, Folder 4)
      - Daguerreotypes (Box 240, Folder 5)
      - Photographic Processes, (2 Folders) (Box 240, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Photographic Processes (Box 241, Folder 1)
      - Woodburytype (Box 241, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1878-1896, (2 Folders) (Box 241, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Essays and Lectures (Box 241, Folder 5)
    - Legal Documents (Box 241, Folder 6)
    - New York Camera Club, 1890 (Box 242, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Box 242, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Techniques (Box 242, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets, (2 Folders) (Box 242, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 242, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Prints and Advertisements (Box 243, Folder 1)
    - Techniques, (2 Folders) (Box 243, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Physics
    - General (Box 243, Folder 4)
    - Advertisements (Box 243, Folder 5)
    - Air Pumps (Box 243, Folder 6)
    - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 243, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 244, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Lecture Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 244, Folder 3 to 6)
    - Meteorology (Box 244, Folder 7)
    - National Standardizing Bureau, 1876-1900 (Box 244, Folder 8)
    - Radium and Radioactivity (Box 244, Folder 9)
    - Sound and Acoustics, (3 Folders) (Box 244, Folder 10 to 12)
    - Weights and Measures (Box 244, Folder 13)
  - Platinum, 1890-1893 (Box 244, Folder 14)
  - Plumbing and Drainage
    - Advertisements, (3 Folders) (Box 244, Folder 15 to 17)
    - Advertisements, (2 Folders) (Box 245, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Articles and Publications (Box 245, Folder 3)
    - Board of Health Plumbing Laws, 1881-1883, (5 Folders) (Box 245, Folder 4 to 8)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 245, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Correspondence, 1874-1921, (2 Folders) (Box 245, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Correspondence, 1874-1921 (Box 246, Folder 1)
  - Potassium
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 246, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 246, Folder 5 to 7)
  - Rare Gases (Box 246, Folder 8)
  - Roofing and Shingles
    - Advertisements (Box 246, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1905-1916 (Box 246, Folder 10)
    - Legal Documents, (5 Folders) (Box 246, Folder 11 to 15)
    - Legal Documents (Box 247, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Box 247, Folder 2)
    - Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 247, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Roofing Case Notes, 1908-1910, (3 Folders) (Box 247, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Roof Shingle Samples (Box 277)
    - Stone Shingle Case, 1915-1916 (Box 247, Folder 8)
  - Rubber
    - Articles and Publications (Box 247, Folder 9)
    - Chandler Manuscript on Caoutchouc (Box 247, Folder 10)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 247, Folder 11 to 13)
    - Correspondence, 1865-1900 (Box 247, Folder 14)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 247, Folder 15 to 16)
    - Legal Documents, (3 Folders) (Box 248, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Adhesives Case, 1896-1897 (Box 248, Folder 4)
      - Austin Day Case, 1870-1882, (2 Folders) (Box 248, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Chewing Gum Case, 1915 (Box 248, Folder 7)
      - Resin Filler Case, 1913 (Box 248, Folder 8)
      - Waterproof Hose Case, 1873-1877 (Box 248, Folder 9)
      - Waste Case
        - Articles and Publications (Box 248, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence, 1891-1892 (Box 248, Folder 11)
        - Legal Documents, (4 Folders) (Box 249, Folder 1 to 4)
        - Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 249, Folder 5 to 6)
        - Patent Specifications (Box 249, Folder 7)
  - Salt
    - Articles and Publications, (5 Folders) (Box 249, Folder 8 to 12)
    - Articles and Publications, (5 Folders) (Box 250, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 250, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1876-1886 (Box 250, Folder 7)
  - Sewage
    - General (Box 250, Folder 8)
    - Advertisements, (3 Folders) (Box 250, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 250, Folder 12 to 14)
    - Articles and Publications, (8 Folders) (Box 251, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Clippings and Notes, (5 Folders) (Box 251, Folder 9 to 13)
    - Correspondence, 1832-1903 (Box 251, Folder 14)
    - New York Infant Asylum, 1896-1897 (Box 252, Folder 1)
    - Silver Springs Case, 1881, (2 Folders) (Box 252, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Shaplegh Cut Out Notes, 1893 (Box 252, Folder 4)
  - Silicon
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 252, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Lecture Notes (Box 252, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1882-1908 (Box 252, Folder 8)
  - Soap
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 252, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1881-1897 (Box 252, Folder 10)
    - Legal Cases
      - Case Notes, 1889-1890 (Box 252, Folder 11)
      - Legal Documents, (5 Folders) (Box 252, Folder 12 to 16)
      - Parsons v. Colgate, 1883 (Box 252, Folder 17)
  - Soda, 1873-1903 (Box 252, Folder 18)
  - Sodium
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 253, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Castner Process
      - Castner Memorials (Box 253, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1893-1904 (Box 253, Folder 5)
      - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 253, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 253, Folder 8 to 11)
  - Spectrum Analysis
    - General (Box 253, Folder 12)
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 253, Folder 13 to 15)
    - Articles and Publications, (5 Folders) (Box 254, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Analyses (Box 254, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 254, Folder 7 to 9)
    - Unidentified Manuscript Article "Spectral Analysis Applicable to Medicine" (Box 254, Folder 10)
  - Steam Pipes
    - Boiler Covering Case (Box 254, Folder 12)
    - Keansbey and Mattison Case
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 254, Folder 13 to 14)
      - Correspondence, 1901-1911 (Box 254, Folder 15)
      - Legal Documents, (7 Folders) (Box 255, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 255, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Steel
    - Harney Steel Case, 1895 (Box 255, Folder 10)
    - Patents (Box 255, Folder 11)
  - Sugar
    - Adulteration-- Clippings and Notes, (9 Folders) (Box 256, Folder 1 to 9)
    - Advertisements (Box 256, Folder 10)
    - American Glucose Co., 1896 (Box 256, Folder 11)
    - Articles and Publications, (4 Folders) (Box 256, Folder 12 to 15)
    - Articles and Publications (Box 257-258)
    - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 259, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Chandler Article on Sugar- Manuscript, (3 Folders) (Box 259, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Beet Sugar, (5 Folders) (Box 259, Folder 6 to 10)
    - Bone Black (Box 259, Folder 11)
    - Cane Sugar, (2 Folders) (Box 259, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Cane Sugar, (6 Folders) (Box 260, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Correspondence, 1868-1904, (5 Folders) (Box 260, Folder 7 to 11)
    - Legal Case-- Kern and Spreckles Case, 1901-1903, (2 Folders) (Box 260, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Maple and Date Sugar (Box 260, Folder 14)
    - National Academy of Sciences Committee on Sorghum, 1881-1885 (Box 261, Folder 1)
    - Patents
      - General, (3 Folders) (Box 261, Folder 2 to 4)
      - Boivon-Loiseau-Chandler Patent, 1870-1876 (Box 261, Folder 5)
      - Leplay-Cuisinier Patent, 1868-1874 (Box 261, Folder 6)
      - Saccharine Patents (Box 261, Folder 7)
      - Seyforth-Chandler Patent, 1869-1876, (4 Folders) (Box 261, Folder 8 to 11)
    - Refinement Processes-- Clippings and Notes (Box 261, Folder 12)
    - Saccharine
      - Correspondence, 1898-1906 (Box 261, Folder 13)
      - Notes (Box 261, Folder 14)
    - Sugar Industry-- Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 261, Folder 15 to 17)
  - Sulphur
    - Articles and Publications (Box 262, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 262, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1876-1901 (Box 262, Folder 3)
    - Patents (Box 262, Folder 4)
    - Sulphuric Acid
      - Patents, (4 Folders) (Box 262, Folder 5 to 8)
  - Tanning Leather and Glue
    - Articles and Publications (Box 262, Folder 9)
    - Clippings and Notes, (5 Folders) (Box 262, Folder 10 to 14)
    - Correspondence, 1872-1912 (Box 262, Folder 15)
    - Glue and Gelatin (Box 263, Folder 1)
    - Legal Cases
      - 1905 Case (Box 263, Folder 2)
      - Pegamoid Co. (Box 263, Folder 3)
      - Peter Cooper Glue Factory Case, (3 Folders) (Box 263, Folder 4 to 6)
      - Quebracho Case, 1908, (3 Folders) (Box 263, Folder 7 to 9)
      - Wet Fuel Case, 1872, (5 Folders) (Box 263, Folder 10 to 14)
  - Tantalum (Box 264, Folder 1)
  - Telegraphy
    - Advertisements, (4 Folders) (Box 264, Folder 2 to 5)
    - Articles and Publications, (5 Folders) (Box 264, Folder 6 to 10)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 264, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1885 (Box 264, Folder 12)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 264, Folder 13 to 14)
    - Patents (Box 264, Folder 15)
  - Telephone-- American Bell v. People's Telephone Company Documents (1 volume) (Box 264)
  - Telephone-- American Bell v. People's Telephone Company Documents, (2 volumes) (Box 265)
  - Textiles
    - Advertisements (Box 265, Folder 1)
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 265, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 265, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Correspondence, 1870-1878 (Box 265, Folder 8)
    - National Academy of the Sciences Report on Wool, 1885-1886, (2 Folders) (Box 265, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Timber
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 266, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Wood Preservation
      - Articles and Publications (Box 266, Folder 4)
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 266, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Correspondence, 1871-1915 (Box 266, Folder 7)
      - Patents, (3 Folders) (Box 266, Folder 8 to 10)
    - Wood Stains, 1906 (Box 266, Folder 11)
  - Tin and Detinning
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 266, Folder 12 to 14)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 267, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1868-1911 (Box 267, Folder 2)
    - Lecture Notes (Box 267, Folder 3)
    - Legal Cases, (5 Folders) (Box 267, Folder 4 to 8)
    - Photographs (Box 267, Folder 9)
  - Toxicology (Box 267, Folder 10)
  - Vanilla- Vanillin Patents (Box 267, Folder 11)
  - Water
    - Advertisements, (2 Folders) (Box 267, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Analysis
      - Analyses (Box 267, Folder 14)
      - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 267, Folder 15 to 16)
      - Chandler Article (Box 267, Folder 17)
      - Clippings and Notes, (11 Folders) (Box 268, Folder 1 to 11)
      - Correspondence, 1884-1892 (Box 268, Folder 12)
      - J.W. Mallet's Data, 1882, (2 Folders) (Box 268, Folder 13 to 14)
      - J.W. Mallet's Data, 1882 (Box 269, Folder 1)
    - Articles and Publications, (14 Folders) (Box 269, Folder 2 to 15)
    - Articles and Publications, (7 Folders) (Box 270, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Clippings and Notes, (8 Folders) (Box 270, Folder 8 to 15)
    - Clippings and Notes, (10 Folders) (Box 271, Folder 1 to 10)
    - Correspondence, 1863-1915, (3 Folders) (Box 271, Folder 11 to 13)
    - Croton Aqueduct, 1884, (2 Folders) (Box 271, Folder 14 to 15)
    - Water Filters
      - Advertisements, (7 Folders) (Box 272, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Articles and Publications, (4 Folders) (Box 272, Folder 8 to 11)
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 272, Folder 12 to 13)
      - Clippings and Notes, (6 Folders) (Box 273, Folder 1 to 6)
      - Correspondence, 1876-1905, (3 Folders) (Box 273, Folder 7 to 9)
      - Lecture Notes (Box 273, Folder 10)
      - Legal Cases- Clippings and Notes, (5 Folders) (Box 273, Folder 11 to 15)
      - Legal Cases- Clippings and Notes (Box 274, Folder 1)
      - Legal Documents, (11 Folders) (Box 274, Folder 2 to 12)
      - Patents (Box 274, Folder 13)
      - Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 275, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Patents (Box 275, Folder 3)
  - Zinc
    - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 275, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 275, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Correspondence, 1860-1909, (2 Folders) (Box 275, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Legal Documents (Box 275, Folder 11)
    - Notes (Box 275, Folder 12)
    - Patents (Box 275, Folder 13)